KATY WELYCZKO SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

katy.jane8@gmail.com510-332-8447

★ katyjane8in kathrine-welyczko♠ katyjane8

SUMMARY

I am a full stack developer with a passion for data and testing. I am highly analytical and process-oriented with indepth knowledge of database types. I thrive in areas that need process improvement and a focus on efficiency. My code experience is supported by 5+ years of dedicated technical project management.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

LANGUAGES TOOLS & FRAMEWORKS

Ruby Ruby on Rails
Java Gradle & Selenium

Typescript Git

Node ActiveRecord

PostgreSQL Docker HTML5 Salesforce

CSS3 Agile Development

JavaScript jQuery
Python Angular
GraphQL React

SASS

EDUCATION

Turing School of Software & Design

August 2017 to April 2018

Logged over 2000 hours with emphasis in Ruby on Rails and JS applications consuming APIs

Ohio University

BA Women's Studies & Film 2005 Emphasis on writing and criticism

ACTIVITIES

TURING SCHOOL STUDENT ADVOCATE -

Leader in Imposters Lunch & Armstrong Posse Lead
Facilitated group therapy sessions and coaching to overcome
Imposter Syndrome. Helped students achieve success by
fostering student support with mentorship opportunities.

GIRLS WHO CODE - LOUISVILLE, CO CHAPTER -

Co-founder and instructor

Taught 7-12th grade girls coding skills through games and real life applications, at the local library

GIRL DEVELOP IT - *Member - Boulder/Denver Chapter* Participated in classes and meet-ups to promote women in technology

THE LOUISVILLE FIBER ARTISTS - Moderator and Founder Weekly knitting and crochet group for women of all skill levels

EXPERIENCE

APTOSoftware Engineer

Denver, CO Apr. 2018 to Current

- Drive feature creation with work in Typescript, Node and JS on a Salesforce backend
- Write automated tests in Java for Selenium WebDriver
- Work in IntelliJ with Gradle to execute test suite and run regressions against custom built API
- Improve API layer with load testing and DevOps tools

VOLTAGE ADVERTISING & DESIGN

Louisville, CO

Digital Producer

Feb. 2017 to July 2017

- Coordinated \$5k \$100k web and design projects for clients such as Reebok and Urban Mattress, with QA for all deliverables
- Facilitated agile workflows with several clients concurrently, including budget updates
- Ran internal meetings, including the daily scrum, and presented at weekly meetings with aggregate updates

CROCS Niwot, CO

Associate Producer & QA Lead Nov. 2012 to Jan. 2017

- Managed go-to-market process within Basecamp, utilizing a combination Agile/Waterfall PM methodology
- Completed QA for on-site assets in HTML format through Sublime Text and Demandware

PROJECTS

BOOKISH (SOLO)

- A tracking app using Goodreads OAuth, Goodreads API, Google Geolocator/Places and the NYT Bestseller List
- Created this dream app to keep track of my Goodreads queue while still supporting local bookstores
- Javascript, JQuery, Ruby on Rails, SASS, Heroku, Travis CI, APIs
- https://are-you-bookish.herokuapp.com/ || https://github.com/katyjane8/bookish

KNIT-WITS (GROUP)

- Multitenancy e-commerce application selling handmade knits
- Executed plan of selling my handmade items, developed stellar Git workflow, and implemented all SASS partials
- · Ruby on Rails, ActiveRecord, SASS
- https://knit-wits.herokuapp.com/ || https://github.com/katyjane8/knit-wits

JOB TRACKER (SOLO)

- Job tracking application utilizing measurable data to create aggregate information
- Ruby on Rails, ActiveRecord, SASS
- https://github.com/katyjane8/job-tracker

IDEA BOX (SOLO)

- Platform for idea storage using authentication for validated users
- Ruby on Rails, Heroku, Paperclip
- https://idea-box-kjw.herokuapp.com/ || https://github.com/katyjane8/idea_box